39 chapter 40 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public domain
Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 40 Poor
Ginger One day, while our cab and many others were waiting outside one of the
parks where music was playing, a shabby old cab drove up beside ours. The horse
was an old worn out chestnut, with an ill-kept coat, and bones that showed
plainly through it, the knees knuckled over, and the for legs were very
unsteady. I had been eating some hay, and the wind rolled a little lock of it that
way, and the poor creature put out her long thin neck and picked it up, and then
turned and looked about for more. There was a hopeless look in the
dull eye that I could not help noticing, and then, as I was thinking where I had
seen that horse before, she looked full at me and said, “Black Beauty, is that
you?” It was Ginger! but how changed!
The beautifully arched and glossy neck was now straight, and lank, and fallen in;
the clean straight legs and delicate fetlocks were swelled; the joints were
grown out of shape with hard work; the face, that was once so full of spirit and
life, was now full of suffering, and I could tell by the heaving of her sides,
and her frequent cough, how bad her breath was. Our drivers were standing together a
little way off, so I sidled up to her a
step or two, that we might have a little quiet talk. It was a sad tale that she
had to tell. After a 12 month's runoff at Earl's Hall she was considered to be fit for
work again, and was sold to a gentleman. For a little while she got on
very well, but after a longer gallop than usual the old strain returned, and after
being rested and doctored she was again sold. In this way she changed hands
several times s but always getting lower down. “And so at last,” said she, “I was
bought by a man who keeps a number of cabs and horses, and lets them out. You
look well off, and I'm glad of it, but I
could not tell you what my life has been.
When they found out my weakness they said I was not worth what they gave for
me, and that I must go into one of the
low cabs, and just be used up; that is what they are doing, whipping and working
with never one thought of what I suffer— —they paid for me, and must get it out of
me, they say. The man who hires me now pays a deal of money to the owner every
day, and so he has to get it out of me
too; and so it's all the week round and round, with never a Sunday
rest.” I said, “You used to stand up for yourself if you were ill
used Ah!” she said, “I did once, but it's no use; men are strongest, and if they're
cruel and have no feeling, there is nothing that we can do, but just bear
bear it— —bear it on and on to the end. I
wish the end was come, I wish I was dead.
I have seen dead horses, and I'm sure they do not suffer pain; I wish I may
drop down dead at my work, and not be sent off to the
knackers.” I was very much troubled, and I put my nose up to hers, but I could say
nothing to comfort her. I think she was pleased to see me, for she said, “You were
the only friend I ever had.” Just then her driver came up, and with a
tug at her mouth backed her out of the line and drove off, leaving me very sad
indeed. A short time after this a cart with a dead horse in it passed our
cabstand The head hung out of the cart tail the lifeless tongue was slowly
dropping with blood; and the sunken eyes!
but I can't speak of them, the sight was too dreadful. It was a chestnut horse with a
long, thin in neck. I saw a white streak down the
forehead. I believe it was Ginger; I hoped it was, for then her troubles would be
over. Oh! if men were more merciful they would shoot us before we came to such
misery end of chapter